Ervin Bond papers, 1915-1989
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Ervin Bond Papers 1915-1989
MS 422
Bond, Ervin
Papers, 1915-1989 (bulk 1965-1985). This collection is comprised of the papers of Ervin Bond. The bulk of the material consists of scrapbooks created by Mr. Bond which contain photographs, news articles and annotations relating to the history of Cochise County, Arizona. The materials include; places, people and events specifically around Douglas, Arizona. Also included are biographical materials; correspondence; articles and speeches; photographs and subject files.
5.50 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Ervin Bond was born in 1906 near Wiggins, Mississippi. In 1926 he moved to Douglas, Arizona where he became a grocer. He married Irma Dalton in 1933 and they had three daughters. In 1956 he began working for the Arizona Highway Department until his retirement in 1977.
Mr. Bond became interested in the history of southern Arizona and began documenting it in the 1960s. He collected materials, oral histories and photographs of Cochise County and assembled many scrapbooks documenting the area. He also lectured extensively about local history. He wrote three books: Douglas, Arizona: its first seventy-five years "and a few before," Percy Bowden: Born to be a Frontier Lawman and Cochise County, Arizona: Past and Present.
Organization
This collection is organized into 6 series:
Series 1: Biographical Files, 1982-1987
Series 2: Correspondence, 1985-1989
Series 3: Articles and Speeches, 1972-1980
Series 4: Subject Files, 1915-1987
Series 5: Photographs, 1983-1984
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1965-1984
Scope and Content Note
Papers, 1915-1989 (bulk 1965-1985). This collection contains the papers of the author Ervin Bond relating to his research on Cochise County, Arizona history. The bulk of the material includes scrapbooks created by Mr. Bond that contain photographs, news articles and annotations about the people, places and events of the area. Other scrapbooks created by Mr. Bond include two on the publication of his book Cochise County, Arizona: Past and Present, lecture events, the bicentennial and special events. Also included in the collection are biographical materials; correspondence; articles and speeches concerning Southern Arizona history and subject files including research materials, newspapers as well as maps included in Mr. Bond's books.
Access Terms
Bond, Ervin, 1906-
Douglas (Ariz.) -- History.
Cochise County (Ariz.) -- History.
Mexican-American Border Region--Photographs
Container List
- Series 1: Biographical Files 1982-1987
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains biographical materials associated with Ervin Bond including résumés, printer plates of articles written about Bond and association member cards.
  - Biographical Material. undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General. 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1985-1989
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains cards from family and letters relating to books written by Ervin Bond.
  - General. undated, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series 3: Articles and Speeches, 1972-1980
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains articles written by Ervin Bond and transcripts of speeches and tours given by Mr. Bond.
  - Dates that Helped Make Our Country Great. undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - My Five Ways to See Cochise Country from Douglas. undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pancho Villa. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scenic and Historic Trips with Ervin Bond. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scenic Tours of John Slaughter's San Bernardino Ranch now owned by the Ramsowers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Some History of the First Baptist Church, Douglas, Arizona. undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series 4: Subject Files, 1915-1987
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains material related to the history of Arizona including newspapers, research materials, maps and printed music.
  - Articles sent to Ervin Bond. undated, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Business Cards. undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Jones, Stan- Printed Music. undated, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Maps- Cochise County. undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Newspapers- Arizona Daily Star. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Newspapers- Bisbee Review. 1948 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Newspapers- Daily Dispatch. 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Newspapers- Stone County Enterprise. undated, 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Research Materials. undated, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Shamrock News- Cochise Hotel article. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Slaughter Ranch. undated, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - State Song- Arizona. 1915-1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Series 5: Photographs, 1983-1984
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains a collage of photographs about the history of Douglas, Arizona, photographs from lectures given by Ervin Bond, photographs of the Bond family and a photo album with photographs of early pioneers and the border region including border conflicts.
  - Bond family. undated, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Douglas, Arizona History. undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Lectures. undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Photo album- Pioneers and Border Wars. undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1965-1984
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series consists of scrapbooks that contain photographs, news articles and annotations by Ervin Bond about the history of Southern Arizona including people, places and events of Cochise County. The majority of the scrapbooks fall under the series titled by Bond: My 5 ways to see Cochise County from Douglas. Also included are scrapbooks of materials relating to the publication of Bond’s book Cochise County, Arizona: Past and Present, lecture events, the bicentennial and special events.
  - Business Cards. undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Geronimo Trail. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cochise County, Arizona: Past and Present- Second Printing. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Highway 80 North East- Leslie Canyon Road. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Highway 80 West. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Highway 92. 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Highway 666- East. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Highway 666- West. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History of my Book Cochise County, Arizona: Past and Present. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Interstate 10- San Simon, Bowie, Wilcox and Benson. 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - My Bicentennial Year- Number One. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - My Bicentennial Year- Number Two. 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Pictures Old and New. 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Pictures Old and New- Ranch Homes and Mexico Wars. 1965-1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pictures- People. 1965-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Places I have Talked. 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sequel to my Last Album. 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Special Events. 1965-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Special Events- Number Two. 1965-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Special Events- July 4th 1979 and after. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)